By now, you see the range
到目前为止
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
of different learning algorithms. Within supervised learning,
你已经见过一系列不同的学习算法
the performance of many supervised learning algorithms
在监督学习中 许多学习算法的性能
will be pretty similar
都非常类似
and when that is less more often be
因此 重要的不是
whether you use
你该选择使用
learning algorithm A or learning algorithm
学习算法A还是学习算法B
B but when that
而更重要的是
is small there will often be
应用这些算法时
things like the amount of data
所创建的
you are creating these algorithms on.
大量数据
That's always your skill in
在应用这些算法时
applying this algorithms. Seems like
表现情况通常依赖于你的水平 比如
your choice of the features that you
你为学习算法
designed to give the learning
所设计的
algorithms and how you
特征量的选择
choose the regularization parameter
以及如何选择正则化参数
and things like that. But there's
诸如此类的事
one more algorithm that is very
还有一个
powerful and its very
更加强大的算法
widely used both within industry
广泛的应用于
and in Academia. And that's called the
工业界和学术界
support vector machine, and compared to
它被称为支持向量机(Support Vector Machine)
both the logistic regression and neural networks, the
与逻辑回归和神经网络相比
support vector machine or the SVM
支持向量机 或者简称SVM
sometimes gives a cleaner
在学习复杂的非线性方程时
and sometimes more powerful way
提供了一种更为清晰
of learning complex nonlinear functions.
更加强大的方式
And so I'd like to take the next
因此 在接下来的视频中
videos to
我会探讨
talk about that.
这一算法
Later in this course, I will do
在稍后的课程中
a quick survey of the range
我也会对监督学习算法
of different supervised learning algorithms just
进行简要的总结
to very briefly describe them
当然  仅仅是作简要描述
but the support vector machine, given
但对于支持向量机
its popularity and how popular
鉴于该算法的强大和受欢迎度
it is, this will be
在本课中 我会花许多时间来讲解它
the last of the supervised learning algorithms
它也是我们所介绍的
that I'll spend a significant amount of time on in this course.
最后一个监督学习算法
As with our development of ever
正如我们之前开发的学习算法
learning algorithms, we are going to start by talking
我们从
about the optimization objective,
优化目标开始
so let's get started on
那么 我们开始学习
this algorithm.
这个算法
In order to describe the support
为了描述支持向量机
vector machine, I'm actually going
事实上 我将会
to start with logistic regression
从逻辑回归开始
and show how we can modify
展示我们如何
it a bit and get what
一点一点修改
is essentially the support vector machine.
来得到本质上的支持向量机
So, in logistic regression we have
那么 在逻辑回归中
our familiar form of
我们已经熟悉了
the hypotheses there and the
这里的假设函数形式
sigmoid activation function shown on the right.
和右边的S型激励函数
And in order to explain
然而 为了解释
some of the math, I'm going
一些数学知识
to use z to denote failure of transpose x here.
我将用 z 表示 θ 转置乘以 x
Now let's think about what
现在 让一起考虑下
we will like the logistic regression to do.
我们想要逻辑回归做什么
If we have an example with
如果有一个
y equals 1, and by
y=1 的样本
this I mean an example
我的意思是
in either a training set
不管是在训练集中 或是在测试集中
or the test set, you know, order cross valuation set where y is equal to 1 then
又或者在交叉验证集中 总之是 y=1
we are sort of hoping that h of x will be close to 1.
现在 我们希望 h(x) 趋近1
So, right, we are hoping to
因为 我们想要
correctly classify that example
正确地将此样本分类
and what, having h of x
这就意味着
close to 1, what that means
当 h(x) 趋近于1时
is that theta transpose x
θ 转置乘以 x
must be much larger
应当
than 0, so there's
远大于0 这里的
greater than, greater than sign, that
大于大于号 >>
means much, much greater
意思是
than 0 and that's
远远大于0
because it is z, that is theta transpose
这是因为 由于 z 表示
x
θ 转置乘以 x
is when z is much bigger than
当 z 远大于
0, is far to the
0时 即到了
right of this figure that, you know, the
该图的右边 你不难发现
output of logistic regression becomes close to 1.
此时逻辑回归的输出将趋近于1
Conversely, if we have
相反地 如果我们
an example where y is
有另一个样本
equal to 0 then what
即 y=0
were hoping for is that the hypothesis
我们希望假设函数
will output the value to
的输出值
close to 0 and that corresponds to theta transpose x
将趋近于0 这对应于 θ 转置乘以 x
or z pretty much
或者就是 z 会
less than 0 because
远小于0
that corresponds to
因为对应的
hypothesis of outputting a value close to 0. If
假设函数的输出值趋近0
you look at the
如果你进一步
cost function of logistic regression, what
观察逻辑回归的代价函数
you find is that each
你会发现
example x, y,
每个样本 (x, y)
contributes a term like
都会为总代价函数
this to the overall cost function.
增加这里的一项
All right. So, for the overall cost function, we usually, we will
因此 对于总代价函数
also have a sum over
通常会有对所有的训练样本求和
all the training examples and 1 over m term.
并且这里还有一个1/m项
But this
但是
expression here. That's
在逻辑回归中
the term that a single
这里的这一项
training example contributes to
就是表示一个训练样本
the overall objective function for logistic regression.
所对应的表达式
Now, if I take the definition
现在 如果我将完整定义的
for the full of my hypothesis
假设函数
and plug it in, over here,
代入这里
the one I get is that
那么 我们就会得到
each training example contributes this term, right?
每一个训练样本都影响这一项
Ignoring the 1 over
现在 先忽略1/m这一项
m but it contributes that term
但是这一项
to be my overall cost function for
是影响整个总代价函数
logistic regression. Now let's
中的这一项的
consider the 2 cases
现在 一起来考虑两种情况
of when y is equal to 1
一种是y等于1的情况
and when y is equal to 0.
一种是y等于0的情况
In the first case, let's
在第一种情况中
suppose that y is equal
假设 y
to 1. In that case,
等于1 此时
only this first row in
在目标函数中
the objective matters because this
只需有第一项起作用
1 minus y term will be equal
因为y等于1时
to 0 if y is equal to 1.
(1-y) 项将等于0
So, when y is equal to
因此 当在y等于
1 when in an example, x,
1的样本中时
y when y is equal to
即在 (x, y) 中
1, what we get is this
y等于1
term minus log 1
我们得到
over 1 plus e to the negative
-log(1/(1+e^z) ) 这样一项
z. Where, similar to the last slide,
这里同上一张幻灯片一致
I'm using z to denote
我用 z
data transpose x.  And
表示 θ 转置乘以 x
of course, in the cost we
当然 在代价函数中
actually had this minus y
y 前面有负号
but we just said that you know, if y is
我们只是这样表示
equal to 1. So that's equal
如果y等于1 代价函数中
to 1. I just simplified it
这一项也等于1 这样做
a way in the expression that
是为了简化
I have written down here.
此处的表达式
And if we plot this function,
如果画出
as a function of z, what
关于 z 的函数
you find is that you get
你会看到
this curve shown on the
左下角的
lower left of this line
这条曲线
and thus we also see
我们同样可以看到
that when z is equal
当 z 增大时
to large that is to when
也就是相当于
theta transpose x is large
θ 转置乘以x 增大时
that corresponds to a
z 对应的值
value of z that gives
会变的非常小
us a very small value, a very
对整个代价函数而言
small contribution to the
影响也非常小
cost function and this
这也就解释了
kind of explains why when
为什么
logistic regression sees a positive example
逻辑回归在观察到
with y equals 1 it tries
正样本 y=1 时
to set theta transpose x
试图将 θ^T*x
to be very large because that
设置的非常大
corresponds to this term
因为 在代价函数中的
in a cost function being small. Now, to build
这一项会变的非常小 现在
the Support Vector Machine, here is what we are going to do.
开始建立支持向量机 我们从这里开始
We are going to take this cost function, this
我们会从这个代价函数开始
minus log 1 over 1 plus e to the negative z and modify it a little bit.
也就是 -log(1/(1+e^z)) 一点一点修改
Let me take this point
让我取这里的
1 over here and let
z=1 点
me draw the course function that I'm going to
我先画出将要用的代价函数
use, the new cost function is gonna
新的代价函数将会
be flat from here on out
水平的从这里到右边 (图外)
and then I'm going to draw something
然后我再画一条
that grows as a straight
同逻辑回归
line similar to logistic
非常相似的直线
regression but this is going to be the
但是 在这里
straight line in this posh inning.
是一条直线
So the curve that
也就是 我用紫红色画的曲线
I just drew in magenta. The curve that I just drew purple and magenta.
就是这条紫红色的曲线
So, it's a pretty
那么 到了这里
close approximation to the
已经非常接近
cost function used by logistic
逻辑回归中
regression except that it is
使用的代价函数了
now made out of two line segments. This
只是这里是由两条线段组成
is flat potion on the right
即位于右边的水平部分
and then this is a straight
和位于左边的
line portion on the
直线部分
left. And don't worry too much about the slope of the straight line portion.
先别过多的考虑左边直线部分的斜率
It doesn't matter that
这并不是很重要
much but that's the
但是 这里
new cost function we're going to use where y is equal to 1 and
我们将使用的新的代价函数 是在 y=1 的前提下的
you can imagine you
你也许能想到
should do something pretty similar to logistic regression
这应该能做同逻辑回归中类似的事情
but it turns out that this will give the
但事实上
support vector machine computational advantage
在之后的的优化问题中
that will give us later on
这会变得更坚定 并且为支持向量机
an easier optimization problem, that
带来计算上的优势
will be easier for stock trades and so on.
例如 更容易计算股票交易的问题 等等
We just talked about the case
目前 我们只是讨论了
of y equals to 1. The other
y=1 的情况 另外
case is if y is equal
一种情况是当
to 0. In that case,
y=0 时 此时
if you look at the cost
如果你仔细观察代价函数
then only this second term
只留下了第二项
will apply because the first
因为第一项
term goes a way
被消除了
where if y is equal to 0 then nearly
如果当 y=0 时 那么
it was 0 here. So
这一项也就是0了
your left only with the second
所以上述表达式
term of the expression above
只留下了第二项
and so the cost of an
因此 这个样本的代价
example or the contribution
或是代价函数的贡献
of the cost function is going
将会由
to be given by this term
这一项表示
over here and if you
并且 如果你将
plug that as a function
这一项作为 z 的函数
z. So, I have here z on the
那么 这里就会得到横轴z
horizontal axis, you end up
现在 你完成了
with this group and for
支持向量机中的部分内容
the support vector machine, once
同样地 再来一次
again we're going to replace
我们要替代这一条蓝色的线
this blue line with something similar
用相似的方法
and see if we can
如果我们用
replace it with a new cost, there
一个新的代价函数来代替
is flat out here. There's 0 out here and then
即这条从0点开始的水平直线
it grows as a straight
然后是一条斜线
line like so.
像这样
So, let me give
那么 现在让我给
these two functions names.
这两个方程命名
This function on the left, I'm
左边的函数
going to call
我称之为
cost subscript 1 of z.
cost1(z)
And this function on the right, I'm going to call
同时 在右边函数
cost subscript 0
我称它为 cost0(z)
of z. And the subscript just refers
这里的下标是指
to the cost corresponding to
在代价函数中
y is equal to 1 versus y is equal to 0.
对应的 y=1 和 y=0 的情况
Armed with these definitions, we are
拥有了这些定义后
now ready to build the support vector machine.
现在 我们就开始构建支持向量机
Here is the cost function
这是我们在逻辑回归中使用
j of theta that we have for
代价函数 J(θ)
logistic regression. In case
也许这个方程
this the equation looks a
看起来不是非常熟悉
bit unfamiliar is because previously we
这是因为 之前
had a minor sign outside, but
有个负号在方程外面
here what I did was I
但是 这里我所做的是
instead moved the minor signs
将负号移到了
inside this expression. So it
表达式的里面
just, you know, makes it look a
这样做使得方程
little more different. For the support
看起来有些不同
vector machine what we are
对于支持向量机而言
going to do is essentially take
实质上 我们要将这一
this, and replace this with
替换为
cost 1 of z,
cost1(z)
that is cost 1 of theta transpose x.
也就是cost1(θ^T*x)
I'm going
同样地 我也将
to take this and replace it with cost
这一项替换为cost0(z)
0 of z. This is cost 0 of
也就是代价
theta transpose x
cost0(θ^T*x)
where the cost 1 function is
这里的代价函数 cost1
what we had on the previous
就是之前所提到的那条线
line that looks like this and
看起来是这样的
the cost 0 function, again what
此外 代价函数 cost0
we have on the previous line that
也是上面所介绍过的那条线
looks like this.
看起来是这样
So, what we have for the support
因此 对于支持向量机
vector machine is an minimizationminimalization
我们得到了这里的最小化问题
problem of one of
即 1/m 乘以
1 over m, sum over
从1加到第 m 个
my training examples of y(i) times cost
训练样本 y(i) 再乘以
1 of theta transpose
cost1(θ^T*x(i))
x(i) plus 1 minus
加上1减去
y(i) times cost zero of theta transpose x(i).
y(i) 乘以 cost0(θ^T*x(i))
And then
然后
plus my usual regularization
再加上正则化参数
parameter like so. Now
像这样
by convention for the Support
现在 按照支持向量机的惯例
Vector Machine, we actually write
事实上 我们的书写
things slightly differently. We parametrize
会稍微有些不同
this just very slightly differently.
代价函数的参数表示也会稍微有些不同
First, we're going
首先 我们要
to get rid of the 1
除去 1/m 这一项
over m terms and this just,
当然 这仅仅是
this just happens
仅仅是由于
to be a slightly different convention that people
人们使用支持向量机时
use for support vector machines
对比于逻辑回归而言
compared to for logistic regression. But here's what
不同的习惯所致 但这里我所说的意思是
I mean, you know, what I'm going
你知道 我将要做的是
to do is I am just gonna get
仅仅除去
rid  of this 1 over m
1/m 这一项
terms and this should give
但是 这也会得出
me the same optimal value for theta, right.
同样的θ最优值 好的
Because 1 over m is just a constant.
因为 1/m 仅是个常量
So, you know, whether I solve
因此 你知道
this minimization problem with 1
在这个最小化问题中
over m in front or not,
无论前面是否有 1/m 这一项
I should end up with the same
最终我所得到的
optimal value of theta.
最优值θ都是一样的
Here is what I mean, to
这里我的意思是
give you a concrete example,
先给你举一个实例
suppose I had a minimization
假定有一最小化问题
problem that you know minimize over
即要求当 (u-5)^2+1
a real number u of u minus 5 squared,
取得最小值时的 u 值
plus 1, right. Well, the
好的
minimum of this happens, happens
这时最小值为
to know the minimum of this is u equals 5.
当 u=5 时取得最小值
Now if I want to take
现在 如果我们想要
this objective function and multiply
将这个目标函数
it by 10, so
乘上常数10
here my minimization problem is
这里我的最小化问题就变成了
minimum of u of 10, u minus
求使得 10×(u-5)^2+10
5 squared plus 10.
最小的值u
Well the value of u
然而 这里的u值
that minimizes this is still u equals 5, right.
使得这里最小的u值仍为5
So, multiplying something that
因此 将一些常数
you are minimizing over by some
乘以你的最小化项
constant, 10 in this case,
例如 这里的常数10
it does not change the value
这并不会改变
of u that gives us, that minimizes this function.
最小化该方程时得到u值
So the same way what I've
因此 这里我所做的
done by crossing out this
是删去常量m
m is, all I
也是相同的
am doing is multiplying my objective
现在 我将目标函数
function by some constant m
乘上一个常量 m
and it doesn't change the value
并不会改变
of theta that achieves the minimum.
取得最小值时的 θ 值
The second bit of notational change,
第二点概念上的变化
we're just designating the most
我们只是指在使用
standard convention, when using as
支持向量机时 一些如下的标准惯例
the SVM, instead of logistic regression as a following.
而不是逻辑回归
So, for logistic regression, we had
因此 对于逻辑回归
two terms to our objective function.
在目标函数中 我们有两项
The first is this term
第一个是这一项
which is the cost that comes
是来自于
from the training set and the
训练样本的代价
second is this term, which
第二个是这一项
is the regularization term
是我们的正则化项
and what we had, we had to
我们不得不去
control the trade off between
用这一项来平衡
these by saying, you know, that we
这就相当于
wanted to minimize A plus
我们想要最小化 A 加上
and then my regularization parameter lambda,
正则化参数 λ
and then times some other
然后乘以
term B, right? Where as I
其他项 B 对吧？
am using A to denote
这里的 A 表示
this first term, and I am
这里的第一项
using B to denote that
同时 我用 B 表示
second term, may be without the
第二项 但不包括 λ
lambda, and instead of
我们不是
prioritizing this as A plus lambda B,
优化这里的 A+λ×B
we could, and so what we
我们所做的
did was by setting different
是通过设置
values for this regularization parameter lambda.
不同正则参数 λ 达到优化目的
We could trade off the relative
这样 我们就能够权衡
way between how much we
对应的项
want to fit the training set well,
是使得训练样本拟合的更好
as minimizing A, versus how
即最小化 A
much we care about keeping the values of the parameters small.
还是保证正则参数足够小
So that would be
也即是
for the parameters B. For the Support
对于B项而言
Vector Machine, just by convention
但对于支持向量机 按照惯例
we're going to use a different
我们将使用一个不同的参数
parameter. So instead of using lambda here
为了替换这里使用的 λ
to control the relative
来权衡这两项
waiting between you know, the first and second terms,
你知道 就是第一项和第二项
we are
我们
still going to use a different
依照惯例使用
parameter which by convention
一个不同的参数
is called C and
称为C
we instead are going to minimize C times
同时改为优化目标
A plus B. So
C×A+B
for logistic regression if we
因此 在逻辑回归中
send a very large value of
如果给定 λ
lambda, that means to give
一个非常大的值
B a very high weight. Here
意味着给予B更大的权重
is that if we set C
而这里 就对应于将C
to be a very small value. That
设定为非常小的值
corresponds to giving B
那么 相应的将会给 B
much larger weight than C than A.
比给 A 更大的权重
So this is just a different
因此 这只是
way of controlling the trade off
一种不同的方式来控制这种权衡
or just a different way of
或者一种不同的方法
parametrizing how much we care about optimizing the first term versus how much we care about optimizing the second term.
即用参数来决定 是更关心第一项的优化 还是更关心第二项的优化
And if you want you can
当然你也可以
think of this as the parameter
把这里的参数C
C playing a role
考虑成 1/λ
similar to 1 over
同 1/λ 所扮演的
lambda and it's
角色相同
not that it's two equations
并且这两个方程
or these two expressions will be
或这两个表达式并不相同
equal, it's equals 1 over
因为 C 等于 1/λ
lambda and it's not that these two equations or these two expressions will be equal. It's equals t 1 over lambda. That's not the case where it bothers that if C is equal to 1 over lambda then
但是也并不全是这样 如果当C等于 1/λ 时
these
这两个
two optimization objectives should
优化目标应当
give you the same value, same
得到相同的值
optimal value of theta. So
相同的最优值θ 因此
just filling that
就用它们来代替
in. I'm gonna cross out lambda here
那么 我现在删掉这里的 λ
and write in the constant C there.
并且用常数 C 来代替这里
So,that's gives
因此 这就得到了
us our overall optimization objective
在支持向量机中
function for the Support Vector
我们的整个优化目标函数
Machine and where you
然后最小化
minimize that function then what
这个目标函数
you have is the parameters
得到 SVM 学习到的
learned by SVM. Finally on
参数C 最后
light of logistic regression, the Support
有别于逻辑回归
Vector Machine doesn't output the
probability. Instead what we
输出的概率 在这里
have is, we have this cost
我们的代价函数
function which we minimize to
当最小化代价函数
get the parameters theta and what
获得参数θ时
the Support Vector Machine does,
支持向量机所做的是
is it just makes the prediction
它来直接预测
of y being equal 1
y的值等于1
or 0 directly. So the hypothesis,
还是等于0 因此 这个假设函数
where I predict, 1, if
会预测1
theta transpose x is
当 θ^T*x 大于
greater than or equal to
或者等于0时
0 and I'll predict 0 otherwise.
And so, having learned the
所以学习
parameters theta, this is
参数 θ
the form of the hypothesis for the support vector machine.
就是支持向量机假设函数的形式
So, that was a
那么 这就是
mathematical definition of what
支持向量机
a support vector machine does.
数学上的定义
In the next few videos, let's
再接下来的视频中
try to get back to
让我们再回去
intuition about what this
从直观的角度看看优化目标
optimization objective leads to and
实际上是在做什么
whether the source of the hypothesis
以及 SVM 的假设函数
a SVM will learn and also
将会学习什么
talk about how to modify
同时 也会谈谈 如何
this just a little bit to
做些许修改
learn complex, nonlinear functions.
学习更加复杂、非线性的函数